Pratik Jaisinghani (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, C#. Net, WEB APIS, Angular, Javascript, Node. js, SQL, Azure, Salesforce



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: SIEMENS Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Amravati Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, C#. Net, WEB

APIS, Angular, Javascript, Node. js, SQL, Azure, Salesforce

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 17-Jan-21 Last Modified: 17-Jan-21

Summary

| have more than 5 years of work experience in developming cloud based products. | have worked with two organizations and both are product based companies. So, | got really good opportunities to showcase my work and develop more new skills. | have done some technical trainings related to Azure Power BI, AWS Web Services, Azure Web Services, etc.

Work Experience

SIEMENS as Software Engineer Oct 2018 to Till Date

In Siemens | started working as a Net Developer. | got an opportunity to work on their legacy desktop application. They had decided to make it as a web application, so in short it was totally a new cloud based product but using some functionalities from existing desktop application. As Siemens work on Agile Methodology, | used to get tasks related to any technology such as AWS Services, Angular 8, Node.js, C# Web APIs. But, | was mainly involved in developing new Web APIs in C# Net, because team was having limited number of resources and no other team mate was more familiar with C#.Net than me.

EXCELLON SOFTWARE as Senior Software Developer Aug 2015 to Oct 2018

I continued to work on these newly developed products by Excellon Software and | was assigned to do some more task on higher level like conducting meetings with client and gathering new requirements by them. In these whole experience, i worked on multiple technologies such as SQL, C#, Azure Web Services, Angular, etc

1/21/2021

EXCELLON SOFTWARE Pune Apr 2017 - Mar 2018 as Software Developer | started working on new upcoming product that was related to GST, As Excellon Software was selected as GSP (GST Suvidha Provider) by our government. In this new cloud based product, my task was to develop Billing and Subscription Module. While working on this, i got a chance to work on Azure Web Services, Angular, etc.

EXCELLON SOFTWARE Pune as Aug 2015 - Mar 2017 Programmer

As a Programmer, | was assigned to work on the company's existing product i.e Excellon 5. It was a cloud based dealership management product. My main part was to do development on new requirements or to modifications in existing

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Prof. Ram Meghe Institute of Technology & Research, Amravati in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C#.Net, WEB APIS, Angular 8+	
Javascript, Node.js, SQL	
Azure, Salesforce	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No